Amiri Baraka papers 6909686
Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Series VIII: Audio/Visual, 1959-2007
  - Film, 1961-1975
    - Color Dub, 'Projects,' Double Xposure, undated; 1 film reels; 3-inch film reel (Box 84)
    - H. Armstron-Negative Duplicate Reel #3, undated; 1 film reels; 3-inch film reel (Box 84)
    - For Trial Auto Shots, P77605-17059, undated; 1 film reels; 7-inch film reel (Box 84)
    - Golpeando en la Selva, undated; 1 film reels; 9-inch film reel (Box 84)
    - untitled, undated; 1 film reels; 3-inch film reel (Box 84)
    - untitled, undated; 1 film reels; 3-inch film reel (Box 84)
    - untitled, undated; 1 film reels; 7-inch film reel (Box 84)
    - Black Music in Transition, undated; 1 film reels; 12-inch film reel (Box 88)
    - Nigerian Dancers, undated; 1 film reels; 12-inch film reel (Box 88)
    - Ghana Dancers, undated; 1 film reels; 12-inch film reel (Box 88)
    - Practice film - pool game etc, undated; 1 film reels; 12-inch film reel (Box 88)
    - Framework of Nation, undated; 1 film reels; 12-inch film reel (Box 88)
      PRES085464
    - Cellar Vigil, undated; 3 film reels; One 7-inch film reel and two 5-inch film reels (Box 88)
    - untitled, undated; 1 film reels; One 7-inch film reel (Box 88)
  - Open reel video, 1971-1997, undated
    - A.F.S. Karamu, undated; 2 videotape (Box 77, Reel 41, Reel 42)
      Sequence of components is unknown.
    - African Liberation Day, undated; 1 videotape (Box 76, Reel 20)
    - African Liberation Day '74, 1975 May 25; 1 videotape (Box 76, Reel 3)
    - African Liberation Support Committee Forum, undated; 8 videotape (Box 79, Reel 103, Reel 101, Reel 99, Reel 102, Reel 100, Reel 105, Reel 104, Reel 97)
    - African Liberation Support Committee panel, Washington, D.C., Day 1, undated; 5 videotape (Box 76, Reel 6, Reel 13, Reel 12, Reel 21, Reel 14)
      Salaudie, Brother Sufu, Abdul Alkalimat. Sufu references opening remarks. Stokely and panel chairman. Stokely, Ahmad, Alkalimat. Questions and answers with Salaudie, Sufu, Alkalimat, Stokely.
    - African Liberation Support Committee panel, Washington, D.C., Day 2, undated; 5 videotape (Box 76, Reel 2, Reel 5, Reel 7, Reel 15, Reel 26)
      Kwadwo, Owusu Sadaukai, Chairman Amiri Baraka. Questions and answers with Owusu, Baraka, Kwadwo. Closing remarks from Locke.
    - African Liberation Support Committee, Atlanta, 1975 April 6; 5 videotape (Box 77, Reel 51, Box 76, Reel 11, Reel 56, Reel 57, Reel 52)
      Opening statement, presentations, questions and answers, and closing statement.
    - African Women's Conference communication workshop, 1974 July 7; 3 videotape (Box 79, Reel 107, Reel 108, Reel 111)
      African Women's Conference workshop, state prison, K. Saulaudin, speakers.
    - African Women's conference panel, 1974 July 6; 3 videotape (Box 79, Reel 115, Reel 116, Reel 119)
    - African Women's Conference workshop, undated; 2 videotape (Box 79, Reel 109, Reel 106)
    - African Women's Conference. Educational workshop Ibura., 1974 July 6; 2 videotape (Box 79, Reel 118, Reel 117)
    - African Women's Conference. Health Welfare, Employment, Staarabisha, 1974 July 7; 1 videotape (Box 79, Reel 110)
    - African Women's Conference. Institutional development., 1974 July 7; 1 videotape (Box 79, Reel 112)
      Anasa, Kimako
    - African Women's Conference. Political workshop., 1974 July 6; 3 videotape (Box 79, Reel 121, Reel 120, Reel 122)
      Lverlen Monroe, Bibi Amina, Joyce Johnson.
    - African Women's Conference. Press conference, Participants, 1974 June 26; 1 videotape (Box 79, Reel 114)
    - African Women's Conference. Social organization., 1974 July 6; 2 videotape (Box 79, Reel 124, Reel 123)
    - Anti-Imperialism Symposium, 1974 April 6; 5 videotape (Box 76, Reel 23, Reel 19, Reel 8, Reel 17, Reel 1)
      Opening Statement by Abdul Alkalimat. Alkalimat, Turner, and Gene Locke speech, Lynn Dozier, and Ron Walters. Amiri Baraka, Jefferies, Owusu, and questions and answers.
    - Baraka interviews ambassador to Tanzania, undated; 1 videotape (Box 77, Reel 46)
    - Basketball Game Staff vs. Coach, 1972 April 15; 1 videotape (Box 76, Reel 28)
    - Blank (M), undated; 1 videotape (Box 80, Reel 132)
    - Boston Busing Crisis, 1975; 1 videotape (Box 78, Reel 90)
      From tape: " Picture very poor, sound bad"
    - Boston Forum, undated; 6 videotape (Box 78, Reel 91, Reel 92, Reel 93, Reel 94, Box 79, Reel 95, Reel 96)
      Jerry Tung questions guardian. Sequence of components is unknown.
    - Bronx Community College, undated; 1 videotape (Box 77, Reel 39)
    - Cab Driver Rally, undated; 2 videotape (Box 78, Reel 88, Reel 89)
    - Cab Drivers' demonstration, undated; 3 videotape (Box 77, Reel 47, Reel 48, Reel 54)
      Newark cab drivers strike. Sequence of components is unknown.
    - Campaign Rally, undated; 1 videotape (Box 77, Reel 34)
    - Community awaits Nazi pickets. 502 High St, 1973 March 10; 1 videotape (Box 81, Reel 155)
    - Congress of Afrikan People Eastern Regional -- Newark, 1971; 1 videotape (Box 76, Reel 4)
    - Crispus King Parada and Imamu at P. Robeson dedication Rutgers. MLK/Malik Shabazz parade, 1972; 1 videotape (Box 80, Reel 146)
    - Don Lee, 1972 May 13; 1 videotape (Box 80, Reel 144)
    - Eastern Regional Conference, Speaking Congress of Afrikan People Reverend, undated; 1 videotape (Box 80, Reel 151)
    - End of Paul Robeson, Simba Soul Session, 1972 April 19; 1 videotape (Box 76, Reel 10)
    - Head Start Afrikan Free School, 1974 February 1; 1 videotape (Box 77, Reel 38)
    - Head Start Convention, 1974; 2 videotape (Box 77, Reel 33, Reel 44)
    - Head Start Fuld House, Leagues, Hilary, 1974 January 30; 1 videotape (Box 77, Reel 43)
    - Hekala/Mwalima Labor Workshop Staarabisha, Statesmen Question and Answers, undated; 1 videotape (Box 77, Reel 36)
      Identified as tape 1; other tapes not identified.
    - Imamu and workers, 1973 March 21; 1 videotape (Box 80, Reel 152)
      Identified as tape 2; first tape in sequence unidentified.
    - Imamu Baraka, 1974 May 30; 1 videotape (Box 77, Reel 50)
    - Imamu's interview with channel 52, undated; 1 videotape (Box 80, Reel 139)
    - Inspection, Angulifa II, 1974 June 22; 1 videotape (Box 77, Reel 61)
    - James Boggs, undated; 1 videotape (Box 80, Reel 147)
    - James Turner, 1974 May 5; 4 videotape (Box 80, Reel 129, Reel 134A, Reel 130, Reel 136)
    - Kawaida Rally, 1973 April 1; 1 videotape (Box 80, Reel 128)
    - Kawaida Rally, 1973 March 18; 1 videotape (Box 80, Reel 153)
    - Kawaida Site Community Support, 1973 March 5; 2 videotape (Box 81, Reel 165, Reel 163)
    - Kawaida Site Ground shots, Kawaida Tower, Henry & Ed, 1973 February 21; 1 videotape (Box 81, Reel 161)
    - Kawaida Site Top of Roof, 1973 March 2; 1 videotape (Box 81, Reel 167)
    - Kawaida Tower, 1973 March 1; 1 videotape (Box 81, Reel 171)
    - Kawaida Tower, 1973 February 28; 1 videotape (Box 81, Reel 173)
    - Kawaida Tower Rally, 1973 March 11; 1 videotape (Box 80, Reel 148)
      Identified as "middle tape," though others in sequence are not identified.
    - Kawaida Tower Site, 1973 February 26; 1 videotape (Box 81, Reel 170)
      Camera man: S.Katibo.
    - Kawaida Tower Site, 1973 March 1; 1 videotape (Box 81, Reel 172)
    - Kawaida Tower Site Roof Top, 1973 February 21; 2 videotape (Box 81, Reel 168, Reel 169)
    - Kawaida Towers, 1973 April 1; 2 videotape (Box 81, Reel 158, Reel 160)
    - Kawaida Towers, 1973 March 11; 1 videotape (Box 81, Reel 159)
    - Kawaida Towers Ground Shots, 1973 February 22; 1 videotape (Box 81, Reel 164)
    - Kawaida Towers Inquiry, 1973 April 16; 7 videotape (Box 80, Reel 127, Reel 133, Box 77, Reel 62, Box 78, Reel 64, Reel 63, Reel 66, Reel 65)
    - Kawaida Towers Rally, 1973 March 25; 2 videotape (Box 81, Reel 157, Reel 156)
      Skit starts off the tape. Umamu speaks. Tapes identified as 3 and 4; first two tapes in sequence not identified.
    - Kawaida Towers roof shots, Onaje, 1973 February 22; 1 videotape (Box 81, Reel 162)
    - Kawaida Towers Site, 1973 February 28; 1 videotape (Box 81, Reel 166)
    - Lecture related to colonialism in Africa, 1976; 1 videotape (Box 76, Reel 27)
      Poor video quality. Sound muddy and difficult to understand.
    - Local TV news interview: Amiri Baraka on Newark housing project, 1974; 1 videotape (Box 77, Reel 40)
    - March on Board of Education, 1973 March 16; 1 videotape (Box 80, Reel 154)
    - May 81 Poetry Beaten Path, 1981 May 1; 1 videotape (Box 81, Reel 174)
    - Multinational Women Conference, BWU 7, 1976 March 6; 2 videotape (Box 76, Reel 18, Reel 9)
      Tapes 1 and 3 of sequence identified; tape 2 (or any additional tapes in sequence) not identified.
    - N.Y.C Committee meeting Political Action, 1974 August 13; 1 videotape (Box 77, Reel 59)
    - National Black Assembly's economic conference, Atlanta, GA, 1975 August 1-3; 1 videotape (Box 76, Reel 16)
      Concessions, Existing Program Part 1, Employment. Identified as tape 2; other tapes unidentified.
    - News people and Ford's speech, 1975 October 15; 1 videotape (Box 77, Reel 45)
      From tape: "Video very bad"
    - Nixon's Farewell Address, undated; 1 videotape (Box 77, Reel 37)
    - Nixon/Watergate/Energy Crisis panel, 1974 May 21; 3 videotape (Box 78, Reel 85, Reel 86, Reel 87)
    - NYC Demo, undated; 1 videotape (Box 77, Reel 53)
    - NYC Student at City Hall, Marching front of City Hall and in Hannis Office, undated; 1 videotape (Box 77, Reel 49)
      From tape: "No picture"
    - NYU, 1976 April 16; 1 videotape (Box 76, Reel 29)
      Identified as tape 3; other tapes not identified.
    - Owusu, 1974 May 19; 1 videotape (Box 80, Reel 150)
    - Oye, undated; 1 videotape (Box 77, Reel 55)
    - Pan-Afrikan Reception, 1974 November 24; 6 videotape (Box 80, Reel 126, Box 79, Reel 125, Reel 134, Reel 149, Reel 137, Reel 131)
    - Paul Robeson's son dedication of Rutgers Center, 1976 March 3; 1 videotape (Box 76, Reel 24)
    - PLO Criteria Class, undated; 2 videotape (Box 80, Reel 142, Reel 140)
      Starts with content from another event. PLO Criteria Class starts at 1:31.
    - Poetry Set NYC, 1976 April 16; 1 videotape (Box 76, Reel 25)
    - Police Repression Rally, 1974 May 20; 2 videotape (Box 78, Reel 69, Reel 70)
      Father Reed
    - Practice Tape Malaika WaChanga Na Super Simba & CWYECP-(Police Cars), undated; 1 videotape (Box 76, Reel 30)
    - Protest against Portguese colonialism in Africa, undated; 2 videotape (Box 80, Reel 143, Reel 145)
    - Rally for Charles Sutton, 1975 October 15; 1 videotape (Box 77, Reel 60)
      From tape: "Picture poor"
    - Sonia Sanchez and D. Lee Set St. Benedicts Auditorium, vidipax, 1972 May 13; 1 videotape (Box 80, Reel 141)
    - Soul Session, undated; 1 videotape (Box 77, Reel 58)
    - Speaker, 1974 July 7; 1 videotape (Box 79, Reel 113)
      Identified as tape 4; other tapes not identified.
    - Spirit House Movers, Boston University, 1972 April 28; 1 videotape (Box 80, Reel 138)
      (Backwards)(Stomp&Love) 1.Stompform 2.Love Poetry 3.Mr. Negro
    - Unidentified Baraka speech and political convention, 1974; 1 videotape (Box 77, Reel 31)
      Start-8:17: video severely distorted, audio too faint to be understood; seems to be a Baraka speech. Rest of tape: no video but audio is clear, sounds like a political convention of some sort.
    - untitled, undated; 1 videotape (Box 76, Reel 22)
      From tape: " To be reused, no picture, check before using "
    - Violence in the schools, 1974 April 21; 4 videotape (Box 78, Reel 72, Reel 73, Reel 74, Reel 75)
    - Walter Rodney, undated; 1 videotape (Box 80, Reel 135)
    - Women in the Struggle panel, 1974 May 23; 3 videotape (Box 78, Reel 67, Reel 71, Reel 68)
      African Liberation Support Committee workshop (start-4:14), Women in the Struggle panel (4:15-end).
    - Youth Workshop, undated; 1 videotape (Box 79, Reel 98)
  - VHS, 1966-2004
    - #67 Women in the Struggle-D.C., 1974; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82A)
    - AB B-Day, 1988; 2 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82A)
    - Africana Studies presents: Amiri & Amina Baraka, 02/03/1989; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82A)
      AFS Media Workshop, Director: Dr. W. McAdoo
    - Africana Studies: Amiri Baraka, Artist-in-Residence, 03/04/1998; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82A)
    - Amiri Baraka Interview for RED HOT + RHAPSODY, 10/28/1998; 2 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82A)
      "A" camera roll
    - Amiri Baraka Poetry Reading St. Bonaventure University, September 1998; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82A)
    - Blue Ark, Black History Month, SUNY at Stony Brook, 02/05/1998; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82A)
    - Blue Ark, Tape 2, 04/02/1986; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82A)
    - Celebration of Margaret Walker, Africana Studies Program, 03/12/1998; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82A)
    - Criticism of the Death's-Head: Memento Mori, 1994; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82A)
    - Dominique DiPrima, Home Turf, undated; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82A)
    - The Spirit of Jazz by Telecom Japan International, undated; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82A)
    - End of a Priest, undated; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82B)
      Czech, Banned in Czechoslovakia
    - Flyers in Search of a Dream (Seg.); The Emperor Jones (Seg.); Bombing of Osage Avenue, undated; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82B)
    - Fried Shoes, Cooked Diamonds; Hell's Kitchen, undated; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82B)
    - Garland Jr.'s Show-Swinging from the Vine, 1997, 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82B)
    - Junius Williams Ks BP, undated, 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82B)
    - Kimako's Blues People, Tape 2, 12/12/1987; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82B)
    - Kimako's, 02/04/1981; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82B)
    - The Kings and Queens of Black Consciousness, undated; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82B)
      Produced by Marvin X
    - Newark African Festival, 1997; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82B)
    - Night and Silence, undated; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82B)
    - Opening Night at Baraka's, 08/07/1987; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82B)
    - Outdoor student protest rally with Provost Edelstein, 03/05/1992; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82B)
      Videotaped by AFS Media Workshop, Director: Prof. William McAdoo
    - Kwanzaa: The Gathering of a People, 1983; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82B)
    - Pan-African Reception, 11/24/1974; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82C)
    - Phoebe Jacobs/James Briggs Murray. Part 2 of 2, undated, 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82C)
    - Poet Billy Capozzi w/ Finally Balanced, 1992; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82C)
    - Rally for Amiri Barakas' Tenure at Rutgers, 03/14/1990; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82C)
      Videotaped: AFS Media Workshop, Directed: Dr. W. McAdoo,, 1990
    - Ras Baraka, Take It Personal w/ Ras Baraka, undated; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82C)
      Show 17: Mumia, Governor's Race, Schools
    - Reisinger Auditorium series, February 06-07, 2004
      - Panel: Coltrane, Monk & Jazz Criticism, 02/06/2004; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 83)
      - Panel: Black Pearls: Blues Women and What They Say, 02/06/2004; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 83)
      - Panel: Blues People, So What, 02/06/2004; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 83)
      - The Rap on the Music Business, 02/06/2004; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 83)
      - African American Dance, 02/07/2004; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 83)
      - Musicians on the Music Part 1, 02/07/2004; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 83)
      - Musicians on the Music Part 2, 02/07/2004; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 83)
      - The Poetics of Music, 02/07/2004; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 83)
      - Amiri Baraka and the Blue Ark, 02/07/2004; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 83)
    - Sonia Sanchez, 05/13/1972; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82C)
    - State of the Arts, undated; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82C)
      Show #1611 Banks/Kanzler/Barraka (sic )
    - Stokely and Chairman, undated, 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82C)
    - Tape #1, undated, 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82C)
    - The Forbidden Land, Alter-Cine', 1989, 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82C)
    - The New Generation Interview with Amiri Baraka, 1966; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82C)
    - Walter Rodney, undated; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82C)
    - Work and Process: X; New York City Opera Co.; Dracula; James Kudel Ka, Michael Baker, undated; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 82C)
- Series IX: Printed Material, 1961-2007
  This series holds printed materials collected by Baraka, but produced primarily by others. There are large numbers of flyers and print announcements and advertisements for Baraka's readings, lectures, appearances, and publications, as well as non-Baraka events across the arts, primarily visual arts, literature, film, and music, are located here. There are also a large number of flyers pertaining to political actions. In addition, this series holds many clippings from newspapers and magazines about Baraka. Also in this series is a large collection of little magazines, literary journals, magazines, and newspapers that contain work by Baraka, as well as copies of a number of his broadsides and books. There is also a large collection of literary journals and little magazines from the 1960s to the 2000s, as well as many socialist, Maoist, and radical magazines, journals, newsletters, and newspapers from the 1960s through the 2000s. Materials are arranged by medium and alphabetically, and much of the material is arranged at box-level.
  - By Baraka, 1961-2004
    - General (Box 148)
    - General (Box 150)
    - Black Theatre #1, 1968 (Box 131)
    - Chapbooks, undated (Box 131)
    - "Get Organized!", undated (Box 146)
    - Jihad Productions--Soul Session: Anthology of the B.C.D., 1969 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Magazines and Literary Journals, 1968-2004(6 Folders) (Box 131, Folder 2-7)
    - Political Pamphlets, undated (Box 131, Folder 8)
    - Preface to a Twenty Volume Suicide Note...--Totem/Corinth Edition, 1961 (Box 131, Folder 9)
    - Totem/Corinth Editions--Four Young Lady Poets, 1969 (Box 131, Folder 10)
    - Books, Magazines, Newspapers (Box 54, Box 136)
    - Broadsides (Box 56)
      - General, undated (Box 56)
      - The Alternative Press, 1997 (Box 67)
  - By Others
    - Books (Box 95, Box 142)
      - General (Box 95, Box 142)
      - Jones, Sylvia--Songs for the Masses, 1978 (Box 131)
      - Books, Magazines, Zines, Journals and Pamphlets (Box 144)
    - Literary Journals (Box 96)
    - Literary Journals (Box 97)
    - Literary Journals (Box 98)
    - Literary Journals (Box 99)
    - Literary Journals (Box 101)
    - Literary Journals (Box 102)
    - Literary Journals (Box 103)
    - Literary Journals (Box 104)
    - Literary Journals (Box 151)
    - Magazines
      - General (Box 105)
      - General (Box 106)
      - General (Box 107)
      - General (Box 108)
      - General (Box 110)
      - General (Box 111)
      - General (Box 112)
      - General (Box 138)
      - General (Box 140)
      - General (Box 141)
      - General (Box 145)
      - Jazz (Box 113)
      - Jazz (Box 114)
    - Newspapers
      - General (Box 115)
      - General (Box 117)
      - General (Box 118)
      - General (Box 119)
      - General (Box 120)
      - General (Box 139)
      - General (Box 141)
      - General (Box 149)
      - African Political (Box 121)
      - "All About Jazz L.A. Issues", 2004-2007 (Box 149)
      - Political (Box 122)
      - Political (Box 123)
      - Political (Box 124)
      - Political (Box 145)
    - Poetry Project Newsletter, (8 Folders) (Box 132, Folder 1-8)
    - Black News, (3 Folders) (Box 132, Folder 9-11)
    - Flyers
      - Baraka, (15 Folders) (Box 125, Folder 1-15)
      - Baraka, (10 Folders) (Box 133, Folder 1-9)
      - Baraka, (5 Folders) (Box 143)
      - Baraka, (3 Folders) (Box 146)
      - General, (6 Folders) (Box 146)
      - General, (3 Folders) (Box 143)
      - General, (10 Folders) (Box 134)
      - General, (11 Folders) (Box 126)
      - General, (12 Folders) (Box 127)
      - General, (10 Folders) (Box 128)
      - General, (3 Folders) (Box 135)
      - General, (6 Folders) (Box 143)
    - Clippings
      - Baraka, (7 Folders) (Box 135)
      - General, (3 Folders) (Box 135)
      - General, (3 Folders) (Box 129)
      - General, (7 Folders) (Box 130)
      - Scrapbook, 1971-1991 (Box 147)
    - Broadsides and Posters, 1968-2005
      - Baraka, 1971-2005 (Box 147)
      - By Others, 1968-2005; (3 Folders)
    - Calendars and Magazines (Box 152)
- Series X: Archived Web Site, 2011-2015
  - Amiri Baraka Web Site, 2011-2015
    Archived web site captures of the official web site of Amiri Baraka, at http://www.amiribaraka.com/. Captured semi-annually, 2011-2015.
    Link to Archived Web Site